# **Cody Yantis**

cyantis@gmail.com 303.748.9508 linkedin.com/in/cyantis

## **SKILLS & QUALIFICATIONS**

IT, instructional, makerspace, supervisory, training, managerial, programming, and metadata experience in public and/or academic libraries

Proficiency in web development (HTML, CSS, and JavaScript), basic Python programming, e-resource and knowledgebase management; familiarity with SQL, R, Sass, and regular expressions

Experience with Voyager, Sirsi/Dynex, Polaris, and Koha/LibLime ILSes

Proficiency in photo/music/video editing and graphic design software; computer hardware and construction; basic network administration; Google Apps; Microsoft, Libre, and Open Office; academic research databases; Apple, Windows, and Linux OSes and software

Experience with curriculum design; assessment and statistics; writing, creating, implementing, and interpreting policy; planning and supervising long and short-term projects; documentation and promotional materials

Communicative, collaborative, organizational, analytical, public speaking, conversational Spanish, and problem solving skills.

**EXPERIENCE** 

# **Jefferson County Public Library** April 2017-present

Adult Services Librarian — Arvada, CO

- Develop and provide library instruction and patron education individually and in groups
- Collect, analyze, and utilize data to adjust programming and library services
- Handle the most difficult patron questions by utilizing complex research skills; provide customer service in reference, circulation, and reader's advisory
- Evaluate and maintain the existing collection through weeding and transferring of materials
- Provide guidance and support in daily operations to staff and volunteers.;
  makerspace initiative committee member

#### **Denver Public Library** April 2013-March 2017

Librarian, Community Technology Center — Denver, CO

- Instruction and curriculum design: computer basics, resume and job skills, computer hardware, privacy and security, web development (WordPress, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Mobile Web Design), Python programming, open-source software and computing, and Microsoft Office
- **Digital media lab programming and instruction:** music, video, electronics, and web development workshops; 3D printing and design; art and design techniques and software; open-source software and computing
- Volunteer coordination; one-on-one technology consultation; staff hiring and training; collection development; IT help desk; reference; digital imaging services; eMedia support; outreach

#### Ruby M. Sisson Memorial Library February 2012-February 2013

Technology Services Librarian — Pagosa Springs, CO

- IT: network administration; PC and software installation and troubleshooting; designed, built, and installed new public computer system; implemented laptop and eReader loan programs; revamped and expanded wireless network; streamlined library website
- Instruction and curriculum design: computer basics, email basics, MS Office series, digital photos, eBooks & eAudio, Skype, blogs & websites basics; hosted twice-weekly tech troubleshooting sessions
- Reference, circulation, shelving, shelf-reading; outreach; tech liaison to the library board

## Jones e-global Library June 2011-January 2012

Digital Services Librarian — Centennial, CO

 Library website design and implementation; tech support and troubleshooting; electronic content and subscription management; creation and implementation of e-reserve systems; oversight of authentication, link resolvers, and proxies; creation and management of metadata; execution of stats, analytics, and usability initiatives; cataloging; collection development; research, development, and implementation of new trends, initiatives, and technologies

**Jones International University / Jones e-global Library** December 2010-August 2011 Acting Director of Learning Resources / Library Tech. Coordinator — Centennial, CO

 Interim library director; design and implementation of new library website; library liaison between university administration, students, and faculty; supervision of librarians and employee training; management of interlibrary loan, reference, collection development, electronic databases, and library tech support; assistance with course development

#### **Serials Solutions** March 2009-December 2010

Senior Data Acquisition Editor — Seattle, WA

 Knowledgebase management, HTML and regular expression coding, data acquisition and editing, bibliographic and metadata maintenance, and provider/client incident resolution; "new employee excellence" award

#### **The Seattle Public Library** September 2008-March 2009

Library Assistant / Directed Fieldwork — Seattle, WA

• Development and implementation of extensive media marketing plan; attendee at numerous city/county refugee and immigrant forums; coordination of programs and community outreach; staffed the ESL/Literacy/World Languages reference desk

## **Columbia University Libraries** October 2007-July 2008

Supervisor, Access Services — The Burke Library, New York, NY

- Supervision and training of fifteen employees in access, circulation, reserves, interlibrary loan, serials, and stacks maintenance; managed the student-employee budget
- Reference; performed tasks for and/or worked closely with special collections, archives, collection development, reference, ReCAP offsite storage, web content management, and cataloging/bibliographic control
- Served on Access Services/Circulation Coordinators, Reserves, Supervisors' Roundtable, and Facilities committees

# Fort Vancouver Regional Library District August 2005-July 2007

Library Assistant — Vancouver Mall Community Library, Vancouver, WA

• Reference, circulation, collection development, book mending, program planning, accounting, shelving, and general public library tasks

**EDUCATION** 

## **Master of Library and Information Science 2009**

The Information School — University of Washington, Seattle, WA

#### **Bachelor of Arts in English Literature 2004**

University of Puget Sound, Tacoma, WA

#### REFERENCES

**Tracy Treece** Senior Librarian, Community Technology Center Denver Public Library, Denver, CO 720.865.1183, ttreece@denverlibrary.org

**Julie Cavender** Web Services / Regional Librarian Education Corporation for America, Birmingham, AL 303.885.0187, jjcavender@gmail.com

**Alison Jones** Manager, Data Acquisition (*formerly*) Serials Solutions, Seattle, WA 502.644.3916, ruealisonjones@gmail.com